[Music]
Hi Welcome to Holistic
Investments ICICI Prove
Platinum Plan is
a right investment
choice for you to achieve your financial dreams. In this video,
we are going to analyze the policy and see if it is right for you. So, let's go into our
video.
Before analyzing this policy, let's first talk about it and
know its details.
This is a link. If you have seen
some of the key features of this Participating Individual Savings Life Insurance Plan,
you will be given two life
cover options to
choose from. You can use it for supplemental income needs and monthly pay
outs. Is it a
Systematic
Withdrawal Plan?  And
you can still boost your savings with the top-up feature
and if you see another cost-effective
structure, what is the benefit? There
is no premium allocation charge and
they give you access to 22 fund options to grow your wealth with the market link return.
And all the benefits you have paid and received so far
have tax benefits. There are many such features as per the respective tax law.
Now if you see the benefits here, there are
two benefits. First of all, the death benefit is
unpersonally. If the policy holder dies before the end of the policy term,
then the
legal heirs
get the death benefit. Of these, there are
two.  Is there a plan option or not?
So growth plus option, protect plus
option, if you see this option below,
all these options are
that time of death or that date
of death, whichever is the highest value,
that is the death benefit or the maturity benefit
given to the nominee or legal heir.
If you see the maturity benefit,
both the options are the same.
When the policy matures, the policyholder will
receive the fund value. So now we have seen that there are such
benefits in this policy.
Now if
you see what are the fund options available here, there
are 22 fund options in it. So if you
see what is that, then Focus 50
Fund India Growth Fund
Opportunities Fund Value Enhance
Fund Multi Cap Growth Fund Blue
Chip Fund Maximize App v Fund
Maximize India  Fund Multi-cap
Balance Fund Active Asset Allocation
Balance Fund Secure Opportunities Fund Income Fund Money
Market Fund
Balance Advantage Fund Sustainable Equity Fund Mid-cap Fund
Mid-cap Hybrid Growth Fund Constant Maturity Fund
Mid-
cap Index Fund Mid-cap 150
Momentum 50 Index Fund Multi-cap
50:25:25 Index Fund Mid Small
Cap 400 Index Fund If
you look at all these funds, they have given a percentage for each
instrument's asset
allocation, like equity,
equity-related securities, depth, money
market and cash, and
each fund differs and this is the
risk of all funds.  They
have categorized the profile as per your choice, from low
to high, so we can
make our choice as per our choice. There are four types of
investment strategies here. First of all, the fixed
portfolio
strategy is where you can
invest your money in any fund option of your choice in the proportion you want and
you
can switch between funds in the middle of the investment amount. You can also switch between funds
through the switch option. In this fixed
portfolio strategy, you
have the option to select an automatic transfer strategy and
your money can come and save something
due to market uncertainty. If you come and save something,
then your savings can be a part or the
whole savings, one or more depth
or equity funds.  You
can keep that fixed amount,
regular, you can also transfer it to an equity depth fund like this and in this strategy, premium re-direction, unlimited free switches, all come with all the target asset allocation strategy next. In this strategy, the asset allocation you choose will be adjusted to your risk appetite, you select it and it will be maintained throughout your policy.
So
your premium will
be divided into two funds, and you can
allocate it according to your
proportion. So they will
rebalance your portfolio every quarter so that
your asset allocation is maintained the same. If
you see the third trigger  Portfolio
Strategy 2 In this strategy, your
savings will come and initially come in two multi-cap
growth funds, which will
come and distribute them, one will be
equity oriented and the other will be
income fund depth oriented.
They will come and distribute them in a 75:25 portion proportion.
This fund
allocation will be
altered accordingly to the market movements
and they will come and rebalance
your portfolio in case of any trigger event. If
you have seen the fourth strategy, Life
Cycle Base Portfolio Strategy,
from the time you start your policy, your savings will come and distribute
them to two funds like this.
Multi-cap
Growth Fund  What will the income fund
distribute based
on your age? So when your age band
moves to another age band, your
fund will base itself on that age and
redistribute accordingly. There are
many fund options, fund
investment strategies like this. Now if you
look at the charges, there is
one called fund management charge. If you
look at this, they
charge 0.70% for money market funds and 135% for all other funds
and 0.50% for discontinued policy funds. If
you look at the policy administration charge,
this is a monthly administration charge.
This is your annual premium and they
charge 0.25% with it. If you had a limited pay policy, then you would have a
single  If you have subscribed to the
premium, they
charge 0.03%. The mortality
charge is for providing you with life cover.
This is based on
your age and gender. If you subscribe to it, they will
charge you based on this.
And these charges are
charged every month when you redeem your units and redeem them based on their address. Next
comes the discontinuance charge. This is
not from the fourth policy year. But
before that, whichever year you
discontinue, they will
charge you based on the annual premium amount. So, there
are multiple charges in this policy and your
premium is invested.  Earlier,
these multiple charges were detected and
invested, so the
principal amount became much less. Overall, in turn,
what
happens over time? Your returns are only getting
worse. So, compare it to other market
link products, but
here there are more charges. If
you look at other market link products, they typically have low charges
and they show
more transparency in their investment process.
But this one does
not have that kind of structure, which is a big drawback. Next, let's
look at the advantages and disadvantages of having this policy. If
you look at the advantages, your maturity benefit is a structured pay-out or
an
income stream that you can receive when it
matures.
You can
receive and add extra funds up to five years, use the
top-up premium feature,
and make
partial withdrawals. First of all,
you can come and use it immediately after the lock-in period ends. With the
systematic withdrawal plan,
you can withdraw a regular amount, a fixed amount, or a percentage of
your fund value regularly. You
can adjust your premium payment frequency as per your convenience. And there
are no premium allocation charges. Your
entire premium is invested in the fund you have subscribed to.
The next
disadvantage is that
this plan has a lot of lock-in periods.  There is a
lock-in
period of like five years, so apart from that,
this surrender partial withdrawal is a bit of a
drawback
and there
is no loan facility and if
you look at the fund options given here, even if they had given 22 fund
options, it would
not be very different or that much
distinctive. And plus, there
are a lot of overlapping investment strategies coming here.
This is also a drawback. And if you look at the premium, they are
investing after detecting a lot of multiple charges. This is also a big
drawback. Over time,
this affects your returns. And if you look at the fund value, they are
only giving you 870 or 75, which is not
accessible. So, this is also a base for choosing your
plan option.  It is only in the
extended policy
term that this is all
a drawback. You should
consider this completely carefully before investing in it. So
now that you have a basic understanding of this policy, let's move on to
our
analysis part. So what are we going to do in the analysis? We will know whether it is worth
investing in it or not and see
what the returns are. For that, we will
put this policy in our browser,
make a benefit illustration base and calculate the
internal rate of return (IRR).
So for an
example, let's say a 45-year-old person
invests 15 lakhs in this policy with an assured amount. So if
you look at the annual premium, it will be 150,000 for the
policy term.  30 years premium
payment term 15 years In this
example,
we have assumed two rates of return,
4% and 8%, this is 8%,
this is the maximum and
minimum that you will get, there is no guarantee, just to
indicate the worst case scenario, they have just mentioned the
two dates of return in their policy
browser,
so we will take that example and
come here and calculate the IRR.
So, what is the actual fund value of this fund value? It
depends on the future investment performance because this is a
market link product.
You have paid all the premiums,
so your maturity benefit is
your fund.  If
your fund value is equal to 4%, your fund
value will be 3620 lacs. If you calculate the IRR using the IC
Proof Platinum Plan Maturity
Calculator,
then it will be 207%.
207% is an interest that is
much lower than the savings bank account rate of interest. If we had
not taken our risk and stayed in the bank,
we would have gotten a
little more than this. So it
seems that it does not provide any kind of essential
value addition.
But okay, this is a worst case
scenario. If you see how it has performed in the best case scenario,
your fund value will
be 9125 lacs. IRR 613.3% is also
lower than a bank FD.  You can
say that in a bank FD you get a
guaranteed return, but in this one there is no guarantee, so in that case there is a
chance of it going even lower. If you
look at this potential return, it
gives lower than a traditional depth instrument, but
this is a fund where we take a risk and invest, I mean, it is
not a policy. It is only by taking our risk and
investing that we get good
returns in the long term, but if we come here and do not get
a risk-adjusted return, then
this defeats the purpose of a market-linked investment
because
we
need inflation-beating returns to accumulate wealth, but this
does not work, so if you invest in this consistently, then you will definitely lose
your
financial  It is
very difficult to achieve the goals. Now, since this
policy does not give a desirable outcome as we thought,
we are going to do a comparative analysis of this with other
investment or alternative
investment strategies.
What are we
going to do? Should we not
invest in this like an investment [ __ ] insurance policy? Should we
separate investment and insurance separately and invest? Let's
see if we get another desirable outcome. So, we have taken a pure term life
insurance policy for a life cover. If you
see the sum assured 15 lock premium, it is
₹32700 for a 25 year policy term and
10 year premium payment term. If
you see the actual, that
Our original annual premium in IC is
₹150000 per year, so by
investing ₹32700,
we
save ₹17300 per year. So let's see if we
can invest separately and achieve higher returns.
If we look at ICICI, they
offer a premium payment term of 15 years, but there is only a 10-year payment period.
So after investing the first 10 years of
insurance premium, we will invest the
remaining balance. Then we can
invest the full premium amount for the following five years. So, according to
our risk appetite, this is our
correct investment avenue.
Investing is a very, very essential thing. If
you are a high-risk investor, you will probably invest in equity. If you
are a low-risk investor, you will invest in depth
instruments. For example, we have invested in depth instruments like PPF Public
Provident Fund
and Equity Mutual
Fund. If you
have seen both of these, they are tax-saving tools. Both have
tax benefits.
So, based on that and having a good track
record, we are going to invest in these two combinations, term
insurance plus PF and term insurance
plus ILS. If
you have seen the PPF scenario, then
you will get the maturity value of that.  At the end of 30 years, you get
9465 lakhs, so with this IRR
you get 629%, so when you
say depth instrument,
PPF comes and a market linked
product, i.e. this IC, Pro
Platinum Plan, has given you its own returns, but it has given you potential out-
performance. Even
if it is a depth instrument, let's
invest in ELSS in combination,
what yield has it given? If you
look at that, its corpus
has given 2.80 crores after 30 years, even if you
detect capital gains tax, the
post-tax value
is 2.47 crores, and you
get 10.50% post-tax IRR, so in this up-
alternative approach, you
have two key advantages: IC Pro  When
compared to the Platinum Plan,
you can access a higher return, alpha generation and liquidity for free.
So, if you
have seen this comparison, you will know that investing in investment and
insurance separately will help you achieve your
financial goals without compromising on returns and liquidity.
So, now the final
verdict is whether to invest in the IC Proof Platinum
Plan or
not.
From our analysis, we have come to know that even if it is a
market linked plan, the
returns from it will be
better than a traditional depth instrument
and more over here.  The
combination of low returns, a lock
in liquidity, and insufficient coverage
all make the
IC Prove Platinum Plan an
unsuitable choice for your investment portfolio.
And this policy also
has a high agent commission. So
what is a better alternative? If you opt for an affordable life cover in a pure term
insurance policy to protect
your family's financial
future, then
you can definitely use the money left over for wealth accumulation. With that,
you can build a
diversified investment portfolio.
This is another effective
strategy that will benefit you in the long term.
icICI Pru
Platinum Plan So definitely you should consider
this approach and invest and
see. If you
want to read more about this policy,
we have posted a blog post on our website and we
have given the link in the description. Definitely go and check it out. If
you
need similar professional guidance or if you think it would be good to have a professional financial planner help you make a
financial or investment decision,
you can book a one-on-one complimentary consultation with our professional financial planner. We
have given the link in the description.
Plus, we conduct regular free live webinars.
You can come to these webinars.  You can learn direct from the leading
experts of the finance industry, not just investment, but financial insights.
We
have also given the registration link for that in the description. If
you liked this video, please like it and
subscribe. We
will meet you again in the next video with more financially beneficial content.
Thank you very much for watching this video.